Have you ever wondered what your unique body odour says about you?
你有没有想过，你独特体味透露了关于你的什么信息？
Turns out, quite a lot!
事实证明，相当多！
From your health to your genetics, we can learn a lot from taking a whiff of your odour.
从你的健康状况到你的基因，通过闻一下你的气味，我们可以了解到很多东西。
Your scent is a complex mix of information, and we humans are pretty good at reading it.
你的气味是信息的复杂混合体，而我们人类相当擅长解读它。
So, what secrets are revealed from our scent, and why do we mostly choose to ignore them?
那么，我们的气味揭示了什么秘密？为什么我们大多选择忽略它们呢？
Researchers believe scent production is mostly determined by our genes.
研究人员认为，气味的产生主要取决于我们的基因。
In a study published in Chem Senses by Craig Roberts and colleagues, participants had to match T-shirts that smelt the same after sniffing them.
在克雷格·罗伯茨及其同事发表在《化学感官》上的一项研究中，参与者需要在闻过T恤后，匹配出气味相同的T恤。
They matched the T-shirts of identical twins, meaning their scent was very similar, and those sniffing had quite an accurate sense of smell.
他们成功匹配了同卵双胞胎的T恤，这意味着他们的气味非常相似，而闻气味的人有着相当准确的嗅觉。
Agnieszka Sorokowska, an expert in human olfaction, says this means "we might be able to detect genetic information about other people by smelling them."
人类嗅觉专家阿格涅什卡·索罗科夫斯卡说，这意味着"我们或许能够通过闻他人的气味来检测其遗传信息"。
But it's not all about your genes.
但这并不全是基因的问题。
In another twin study called 'The Discrimination of Human Odour by the Dog', a dog could distinguish the odour of identical twins living apart.
在另一项名为"狗对人类气味的辨别"的双胞胎研究中，一只狗能够分清分开生活的同卵双胞胎的气味。
So, your environment can change how you smell, but it might take a dog's sensitive nose to detect it.
所以，你的环境可以改变你的气味，但可能只有拥有灵敏鼻子的狗才能察觉到。
Even your health can change how you smell.
甚至你的健康状况也会改变你的气味。
In a study called 'The Scent of Disease', the BO of someone with diabetes was associated with rotten apples, while those with scurvy had sweat described as 'putrid'.
在一项名为"疾病的气味"的研究中，糖尿病患者的体味类似烂苹果的味道，而坏血病患者的汗水则被描述为"腐烂的"。
Odour research has also helped to train dogs to detect illnesses such as cancer by scent alone.
气味研究还帮助训练狗仅通过气味就能检测出癌症等疾病。
Do humans use any of this information?
人类会使用这些信息吗？
King Louis XIV of France was known to douse his palace in fragrance, perhaps to mask the stench of poor personal hygiene.
法国国王路易十四以用香水浸洒他的宫殿而闻名，也许是为了掩盖个人卫生不佳的恶臭。
This trend continues today – many of us cover our natural body odour with sweet or floral-smelling perfumes, and in the process, we may be losing the opportunity to learn more about each other and the world.
这种趋势延续至今——我们中的许多人用甜味或花香味的香水来掩盖自然的体味，在这个过程中，我们可能正在失去更多地了解彼此和世界的机会。
Maybe it's time to drop the deodorants and pleasant aroma of your favourite perfume and let your natural scent waft around, sending the signals that your body wants to emit.
也许是时候放下除臭剂和你最喜欢的香水那怡人的香气，让你自然的体味飘散开来，传递你的身体想要发出的信号了。